<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BeZikaFree</string>

    <string name="symptoms_title">What are the symptoms of Zika?</string>
    <string name="symptoms_text">The Zika virus commonly causes a mild flu-like illness that might include fever, headache, joint and or muscle pain, conjunctivitis (“pink eye”) and sometimes a body rash.\n\nMost people infected with Zika virus won’t have symptoms. For this reason, many people might not realize they have been infected. It is estimated that only one out of five infected people will have symptoms. The most common symptoms of Zika are fever, rash, joint pain, or conjunctivitis (red eyes). Other common symptoms include muscle pain and headache.\n\nThe illness is usually mild. Symptoms begin 3 to 7 days after being infected and can last for several days to a week. People usually don’t get sick enough to go to the hospital, and they very rarely die of Zika.\n\nZika virus usually remains in the blood of an infected person for about a week but it can be found longer in some people. Once a person has been infected, he or she is likely to be protected from future infections.\n\nSee your doctor or other healthcare provider if you are pregnant and develop a fever, rash, joint pain, or red eyes within 2 weeks after traveling to a place where Zika has been reported. Be sure to tell your doctor or other healthcare provider where you traveled.</string>
    <string name="overview_title">What is Zika?</string>
    <string name="overview_text">The Zika virus is a mosquito-borne illness, meaning people can get the virus by being bitten by an infected mosquito. Zika virus is related to dengue, yellow fever and West Nile Virus. It was first identified in 1947. In 2013 there were outbreaks of illness from Zika virus in several Pacific islands. More recently, the virus has been reported in many Central and South American countries. Beginning in late 2015, cases of Zika virus have been reported in some U.S. states. These are people who were infected while traveling to these countries.</string>
    <string name="transmission_mosquito_title">Through Mosquito Bites</string>
    <string name="transmission_mosquito_text">Zika virus is transmitted to people primarily through the bite of an infected Aedes species mosquito (A. aegypti and A. albopictus). These are the same mosquitoes that spread dengue and chikungunya viruses. \n\nThese mosquitoes typically lay eggs in and near standing water in things like buckets, bowls, animal dishes, flower pots and vases. They prefer to bite people, and live indoors and outdoors near people. \n\nMosquitoes become infected when they feed on a person already infected with the virus. Infected mosquitoes can then spread the virus to other people through bites.</string>
    <string name="transmission_mother_title">From Mother to Child</string>
    <string name="transmission_mother_text">A pregnant woman can pass Zika virus to her fetus during pregnancy. Zika is a cause of microcephaly and other severe fetal brain defects. We are studying the full range of other potential health problems that Zika virus infection during pregnancy may cause. \n\nA pregnant woman already infected with Zika virus can pass the virus to her fetus during the pregnancy or around the time of birth. \n\nTo date, there are no reports of infants getting Zika virus through breastfeeding. Because of the benefits of breastfeeding, mothers are encouraged to breastfeed even in areas where Zika virus is found.</string>
    <string name="transmission_transfusion_title">Through Blood Transfusion</string>
    <string name="transmission_transfusion_text">As of February, 1, 2016, there have not been any confirmed blood transfusion transmission cases in the United States. \n\nThere have been multiple reports of blood transfusion transmission cases in Brazil. These reports are currently being investigated. \n\nDuring the French Polynesian outbreak, 2.8% of blood donors tested positive for Zika and in previous outbreaks, the virus has been found in blood donors.</string>
    <string name="transmission_sex_title">Through Sexual Contact</string>
    <string name="transmission_sex_text">Zika virus can be spread by a man to his sex partners. \n\nIn known cases of sexual transmission, the men developed Zika virus symptoms. From these cases, we know the virus can be spread when the man has symptoms, before symptoms start and after symptoms resolve. \n\nIn one case, the virus was spread a few days before symptoms developed. \n\nThe virus is present in semen longer than in blood.</string>
    <string name="transmission_father_title">What if the father of the baby is infected with the Zika virus or has been in an area where Zika is active?</string>
    <string name="transmission_father_text">Zika virus can be found in semen and sexual transmission of the virus has been reported. We do not know how often Zika infection can be found in semen or how long the virus can be present in semen. Consistent and regular condom use is recommended for women if a man has a current diagnosis of Zika infection, a man has symptoms of Zika, or a man has recently been in a place where there is known Zika transmission, even if he has had no symptoms. A man who has returned from an area of active Zika transmission but has not had any symptoms should consider using a condom for 28 days after his return to prevent the chance of sexual transmission to his non-pregnant partner.</string>
    <string name="effects_risks_title">Background Risks</string>
    <string name="effects_risks_text">In every pregnancy a woman starts out with a 3-5% chance of having a baby with a birth defect. This is called her background risk. This sheet talks about whether exposure to the Zika virus may increase the risk for birth defects over that background risk. This information should not take the place of medical care and advice from your health care provider.</string>
    <string name="effects_breastfeeding_title">Breastfeeding with Zika</string>
    <string name="effects_breastfeeding_text">The Brazilian Ministry of Health and the CDC state that with our current understanding, breastfeeding should not be interrupted. At this time there is no information on possible effects to the baby in a breastfeeding mother who has the Zika virus. Be sure to talk to your health care provider about all your choices for breastfeeding.</string>
    <string name="effects_pregnancy_title">Can Zika Virus Affect my Pregnancy?</string>
    <string name="effects_pregnancy_text">In April 2016, the CDC announced that there is now enough evidence to conclude that Zika virus infection during pregnancy is a cause of microcephaly (small head and brain) and other severe fetal brain defects. Other abnormalities are also associated with Zika virus infection during pregnancy. Mothers of these babies described rash and flu-like illnesses during their pregnancies and some have tested positive for the Zika virus. Research is continuing to determine the risk of adverse pregnancy outcomes in babies whose mothers had the Zika virus in pregnancy. \n\n Pregnant women can be infected with Zika virus in any trimester (4,7,8). The incidence of Zika virus infection in pregnant women is not currently known, and data on pregnant women infected with Zika virus are limited. No evidence exists to suggest that pregnant women are more susceptible to Zika virus infection or experience more severe disease during pregnancy. \n\n Maternal-fetal transmission of Zika virus has been documented throughout pregnancy (4,7,8). Although Zika virus RNA has been detected in the pathologic specimens of fetal losses (4), it is not known if Zika virus caused the fetal losses. Zika virus infections have been confirmed in infants with microcephaly (4), and in the current outbreak in Brazil, a marked increase in the number of infants born with microcephaly has been reported (9). However, it is not known how many of the microcephaly cases are associated with Zika virus infection. Studies are under way to investigate the association of Zika virus infection and microcephaly, including the role of other contributory factors (e.g., prior or concurrent infection with other organisms, nutrition, and environment). The full spectrum of outcomes that might be associated with Zika virus infections during pregnancy is unknown and requires further investigation.</string>
    <string name="effects_pregnancy2_title">Before I got pregnant I was in a country with active Zika. What if I had Zika then, even without symptoms? Is there a chance of a problem for the baby?</string>
    <string name="effects_pregnancy2_text">Zika virus usually remains in the blood of an infected person for a few days to a week. The virus will not cause infection in a baby that is conceived after the virus is cleared from the mother’s blood. If you conceived very shortly before or after returning from an area with active Zika, you should speak to your health care provider, regardless of symptoms. There is currently no evidence that Zika virus infection increases the chance of birth defects in future pregnancies. Again, the chance of a problem for the baby when the mother has Zika infection in her pregnancy is not well understood.</string>
    <string name="effects_microcephaly_title">Facts about Microcephaly</string>
    <string name="effects_microcephaly_text">Microcephaly is a birth defect where a baby’s head is smaller than expected when compared to babies of the same sex and age. Babies with microcephaly often have smaller brains that might not have developed properly.\n\n Microcephaly is a condition where a baby’s head is much smaller than expected. During pregnancy, a baby’s head grows because the baby’s brain grows. Microcephaly can occur because a baby’s brain has not developed properly during pregnancy or has stopped growing after birth, which results in a smaller head size. Microcephaly can be an isolated condition, meaning that it can occur with no other major birth defects, or it can occur in combination with other major birth defects.\n\n Severe microcephaly is a more serious, extreme form of this condition where a baby’s head is much smaller than expected. Severe microcephaly can result because a baby’s brain has not developed properly during pregnancy, or the brain started to develop correctly and then was damaged at some point during pregnancy.\n\n Babies with microcephaly can have a range of other problems, depending on how severe their microcephaly is. Microcephaly has been linked with the following problems:\n\n \t\t• Seizures \n \t\t• Developmental delay, such as problems with speech or other developmental milestones (like sitting, standing, and walking) \n \t\t• Intellectual disability (decreased ability to learn and function in daily life) \n \t\t• Problems with movement and balance \n \t\t• Feeding problems, such as difficulty swallowing \n \t\t• Hearing loss \n \t\t• Vision problems \n\n These problems can range from mild to severe and are often lifelong. Because the baby’s brain is small and underdeveloped, babies with severe microcephaly can have more of these problems, or have more difficulty with them, than babies with milder microcephaly. Severe microcephaly also can be life-threatening. Because it is difficult to predict at birth what problems a baby will have from microcephaly, babies with microcephaly often need close follow-up through regular check-ups with a healthcare provider to monitor their growth and development.</string>
    <string name="prevention_title">Prevention</string>
    <string name="prevention_text">Prevention is the best approach for protection. That includes using an EPA approved insect repellent, wearing protective clothing (such as long sleeves and long pants and/or clothing treated with permethrin), and removing standing water where mosquitoes live and breed. When possible, air-conditioning or screens should be used to keep mosquitoes out of the home. More information is available on The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) webpage Zika Virus Prevention. MotherToBaby fact sheets are available for the insect repellent DEET and information about the insecticide permethrin is included on our Pesticides and Pregnancy fact sheet.</string>
    <string name="prevention_preventBites_title">Steps to Prevent Zika - Prevent Bites</string>
    <string name="prevention_preventBites_text">When in areas with Zika and other diseases spread by mosquitoes, take the following steps:\n\n \t\t • Wear long-sleeved shirts and long pants. \n \t\t • Stay in places with air conditioning and window and door screens to keep mosquitoes outside. \n \t\t • Take steps to control mosquitoes inside and outside your home. \n \t\t • Sleep under a mosquito bed net if you are overseas or outside and are not able to protect yourself from mosquito bites.\n \t\t • Use Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)-registered insect repellents with one of the following active ingredients: DEET, picaridin, IR3535, oil of lemon eucalyptus, or para-menthane-diol. Choosing an EPA-registered repellent ensures the EPA has evaluated the product for effectiveness. When used as directed, EPA-registered insect repellents are proven safe and effective, even for pregnant and breast-feeding women.\n \t\t •Treat clothing and gear with permethrin or purchase permethrin-treated items. \n\n Even if they do not feel sick, travelers returning to the United States from an area with Zika should take steps to prevent mosquito bites for 3 weeks so they do not spread Zika to mosquitoes that could spread the virus to other people.</string>
    <string name="prevention_control_outsideHome_title">Control Mosquitoes Outside Home</string>
    <string name="prevention_control_outsideHome_text">• Install or repair and use window and door screens. Do not leave doors propped open.\n\n • Once a week, empty and scrub, turn over, cover, or throw out any items that hold water like tires, buckets, planters, toys, pools, birdbaths, flowerpot saucers, or trash containers. Mosquitoes lay eggs near water. \n\n • Tightly cover water storage containers (buckets, cisterns, rain barrels) so that mosquitoes cannot get inside to lay eggs. \n\n • For containers without lids, use wire mesh with holes smaller than an adult mosquito.\n\n • Use larvicides to treat large containers of water that will not be used for drinking and cannot be covered or dumped out. \n\n • Use an outdoor flying insect spray where mosquitoes rest. Mosquitoes rest in dark, humid areas like under patio furniture, or under the carport or garage. When using insecticides, always follow label instructions. \n\n • If you have a septic tank, repair cracks or gaps. Cover open vent or plumbing pipes. Use wire mesh with holes smaller than an adult mosquito.</string>
    <string name="prevention_control_insideHome_title">Control Mosquitoes Inside Home</string>
    <string name="prevention_control_insideHome_text">• Keep windows and doors shut and use air conditioning when possible.\n\n • Keep mosquitoes from laying eggs inside your home. Once a week, empty and scrub, turn over, cover, or throw out any items that hold water like vases and flowerpot saucers.\n\n • Kill mosquitoes inside your home. Use an indoor flying insect fogger* or indoor insect spray* to kill mosquitoes and treat areas where they rest. These products work immediately, but may need to be reapplied. Always follow label directions. Only using insecticide will not keep your home free of mosquitoes.\n\n • Mosquitoes rest in dark, humid places like under the sink, in closets, under furniture, or in the laundry room.\n\n • Use an indoor fogger* or indoor insect spray* to reach and treat areas were mosquitos rest inside the home.</string>
    <string name="prevention_safeSex_protectOthers_title">Protect Others</string>
    <string name="prevention_safeSex_protectOthers_text">• Zika virus can be spread during sex by a man infected with Zika to his sex partners.\n • To help prevent spreading Zika from sex, you can use condoms, correctly from start to finish, every time you have sex. This includes vaginal, anal, and oral (mouth-to-penis) sex. Condoms also prevent HIV and other STDs. Not having sex is the only way to be sure that someone does not get sexually transmitted Zika virus.</string>
    <string name="prevention_safeSex_condomDoDont_title">The Right Way to Use a Male Condom</string>
    <string name="prevention_safeSex_condomDoDont_text">• DO use a condom every time you have sex.\n • DO put on a condom before having sex.\n • DO read the package and check the expiration date.\n • DO make sure there are no tears or defects.\n • DO store condoms in a cool, dry place.\n • DO use latex or polyurethane condoms.\n • DO use water or silicone-based lubricant to prevent breakage.\n • DO remember that condoms come in many sizes and thicknesses, so find a brand that works best for you and your partner.\n\n • DON’T store condoms in a car or keep them in your wallet.\n • DON’T use nonoxynol-9 (a spermicide), as this can cause irritation.\n • DON’T use oil-based products like baby oil, lotion, petroleum jelly, or cooking oil because they will cause the condom to break.\n • DON’T use more than one condom at a time.\n • DON’T reuse a condom.\n • DON’T flush condoms as they may clog the toilet.</string>
    <string name="prevention_safeSex_condomUse_title">How To Put On and Take Off a Male Condom</string>
    <string name="prevention_safeSex_condomUse_text">• Carefully open and remove condom from wrapper.\n • Place condom on the head of the erect, hard penis. If uncircumcised, pull back the foreskin first. \n • Pinch air out of the tip of the condom.\n • Unroll condom all the way down the penis.\n • After sex but before pulling out, hold the condom at the base and withdraw the penis.\n • Carefully remove the condom and throw it in the trash.</string>
    <string name="prevention_travel_protectiveMeasures_title">General Protective Measures</string>
    <string name="prevention_travel_protectiveMeasures_text">• Avoid outbreaks. To the extent possible, travelers should avoid known foci of epidemic disease transmission. The CDC Travelers’ Health website provides updates on regional disease transmission patterns and outbreaks (www.cdc.gov/travel).\n\n • Be aware of peak exposure times and places. Exposure to arthropod bites may be reduced if travelers modify their patterns or locations of activity. Although mosquitoes may bite at any time of day, peak biting activity for vectors of some diseases (such as dengue and chikungunya) is during daylight hours. Vectors of other diseases (such as malaria) are most active in twilight periods (dawn and dusk) or in the evening after dark. Avoiding the outdoors or taking preventive actions (such as using repellent) during peak biting hours may reduce risk. Place also matters; ticks and chiggers are often found in grasses, woodlands, or other vegetated areas. Local health officials or guides may be able to point out areas with increased arthropod activity.\n\n • Wear appropriate clothing. Travelers can minimize areas of exposed skin by wearing long-sleeved shirts, long pants, boots, and hats. Tucking in shirts, tucking pants into socks, and wearing closed shoes instead of sandals may reduce risk. Repellents or insecticides, such as permethrin, can be applied to clothing and gear for added protection. (Additional information on clothing is below.)\n\n • Check for ticks. Travelers should inspect themselves and their clothing for ticks during outdoor activity and at the end of the day. Prompt removal of attached ticks can prevent some infections. Showering within 2 hours of being in a tick-infested area reduces the risk of some tickborne diseases.\n\n • Bed nets. When accommodations are not adequately screened or air conditioned, bed nets are essential in providing protection and reducing discomfort caused by biting insects. If bed nets do not reach the floor, they should be tucked under mattresses. Bed nets are most effective when they are treated with a pyrethroid insecticide. Pretreated, long-lasting bed nets can be purchased before traveling, or nets can be treated after purchase. Effective, treated nets may also be available in destination countries. Nets treated with a pyrethroid insecticide will be effective for several months if they are not washed. Long-lasting pretreated nets may be effective for much longer.\n\n • Insecticides and spatial repellents. More spatial repellent products are becoming commercially available. These products, containing active ingredients such as metofluthrin and allethrin, augment aerosol insecticide sprays, vaporizing mats, and mosquito coils that have been available for some time. Such products can help to clear rooms or areas of mosquitoes (spray aerosols) or repel mosquitoes from a circumscribed area (coils, spatial repellents). Although many of these products appear to have repellent or insecticidal activity under particular conditions, they have not yet been adequately evaluated in peer-reviewed studies for their efficacy in preventing vectorborne disease. Travelers should supplement the use of these products with repellent on skin or clothing and using bed nets in areas where vectorborne diseases are a risk or biting arthropods are noted. Since some products available internationally may contain pesticides that are not registered in the United States, it may be preferable for travelers to bring their own. Insecticides and repellent products should always be used with caution, avoiding direct inhalation of spray or smoke.</string>
    <string name="prevention_travel_women_title">Recommendations for Pregnant Women Considering Travel to an Area of Zika Virus Transmission</string>
    <string name="prevention_travel_women_text">Because there is neither a vaccine nor prophylactic medications available to prevent Zika virus infection, CDC recommends that all pregnant women consider postponing travel to areas where Zika virus transmission is ongoing (10). If a pregnant woman travels to an area with Zika virus transmission, she should be advised to strictly follow steps to avoid mosquito bites (11,12). Mosquitoes that spread Zika virus bite both indoors and outdoors, mostly during the daytime; therefore, it is important to ensure protection from mosquitoes throughout the entire day (13). Mosquito prevention strategies include wearing long-sleeved shirts and long pants, using U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)–registered insect repellents, using permethrin-treated clothing and gear, and staying and sleeping in screened-in or air-conditioned rooms. When used as directed on the product label, insect repellents containing DEET, picaridin, and IR3535 are safe for pregnant women (14,15). Further guidelines for using insect repellents are available online (http://wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/page/avoid-bug-bites) (11,15).</string>
    <string name="prevention_travel_pregnantWomen_title">Recommendations for Pregnant Women with History of Travel to an Area of Zika Virus Transmission</string>
    <string name="prevention_travel_pregnantWomen_text">Health care providers should ask all pregnant women about recent travel. Women who traveled to an area with ongoing Zika virus transmission during pregnancy should be evaluated for Zika virus infection and tested in accordance with CDC Interim Guidance (Figure). Because of the similar geographic distribution and clinical presentation of Zika, dengue, and chikungunya virus infection, patients with symptoms consistent with Zika virus disease should also be evaluated for dengue and chikungunya virus infection, in accordance with existing guidelines (16,17).\n\n Zika virus testing of maternal serum includes reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) testing for symptomatic patients with onset of symptoms within the previous week. Immunoglobulin M (IgM) and neutralizing antibody testing should be performed on specimens collected ≥4 days after onset of symptoms. Cross-reaction with related flaviviruses (e.g., dengue or yellow fever) is common with antibody testing, and thus it might be difficult to distinguish Zika virus infection from other flavivirus infections. Consultation with state or local health departments might be necessary to assist with interpretation of results (18). Testing of asymptomatic pregnant women is not recommended in the absence of fetal microcephaly or intracranial calcifications.\n\n Zika virus RT-PCR testing can be performed on amniotic fluid (7,9). Currently, it is unknown how sensitive or specific this test is for congenital infection. Also, it is unknown if a positive result is predictive of a subsequent fetal abnormality, and if so, what proportion of infants born after infection will have abnormalities. Amniocentesis is associated with an overall 0.1% risk of pregnancy loss when performed at less than 24 weeks of gestation (19). Amniocentesis performed ≥15 weeks of gestation is associated with lower rates of complications than those performed at earlier gestational ages, and early amniocentesis (≤14 weeks of gestation) is not recommended (20). Health care providers should discuss the risks and benefits of amniocentesis with their patients. A positive RT-PCR result on amniotic fluid would be suggestive of intrauterine infection and potentially useful to pregnant women and their health care providers (20).\n\n For a live birth with evidence of maternal or fetal Zika virus infection, the following tests are recommended: histopathologic examination of the placenta and umbilical cord; testing of frozen placental tissue and cord tissue for Zika virus RNA; and testing of cord serum for Zika and dengue virus IgM and neutralizing antibodies. CDC is developing guidelines for infants infected by Zika virus. If a pregnancy results in a fetal loss in a woman with history of travel to an area of Zika virus transmission with symptoms consistent with Zika virus disease during or within 2 weeks of travel or findings of fetal microcephaly, Zika virus RT-PCR and immunohistochemical staining should be performed on fetal tissues, including umbilical cord and placenta.\n\n There is no commercially available test for Zika virus. Testing for Zika virus infection is performed at CDC and several state health departments. Health care providers should contact their state or local health department to facilitate testing and for assistance with interpreting results (4).</string>
    <string name="treatment_cure_title">Treatment</string>
    <string name="treatment_cure_text">Treat the symptoms:\n \t\t• Get plenty of rest. \n \t\t• Drink fluids to prevent dehydration. \n \t\t• Take medicine such as acetaminophen (Tylenol®) or paracetamol to reduce fever and pain.\n \t\t• Do not take aspirin and other non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDS) until dengue can be ruled out to reduce the risk of bleeding.\n \t\t• If you are taking medicine for another medical condition, talk to your doctor or other healthcare provider before taking additional medication. \n\n If you have Zika, prevent mosquito bites for the first week of your illness.\n • During the first week of infection, Zika virus can be found in the blood and passed from an infected person to a mosquito through mosquito bites.\n • An infected mosquito can then spread the virus to other people.</string>
    <string name="treatment_cure_symptoms_title">There is No Vaccine to Prevent or Medicine to Treat Zika Virus.</string>
    <string name="treatment_cure_symptoms_text">Treatment is limited to relieving the symptoms of Zika virus: reducing fever, headache, joint pain, pink eye, and any other symptoms that might develop.</string>
    <string name="treatment_cure_pregnant_title">How to Treat Pregnant Women with Diagnoses of Zika Virus Disease</string>
    <string name="treatment_cure_pregnant_text">No specific antiviral treatment is available for Zika virus disease. Treatment is generally supportive and can include rest, fluids, and use of analgesics and antipyretics (4). Fever should be treated with acetaminophen (21). Although aspirin and other nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs are not typically used in pregnancy, these medications should specifically be avoided until dengue can be ruled out to reduce the risk for hemorrhage (4,9,17).\n\n In a pregnant woman with laboratory evidence of Zika virus in serum or amniotic fluid, serial ultrasounds should be considered to monitor fetal anatomy and growth every 3–4 weeks. Referral to a maternal-fetal medicine or infectious disease specialist with expertise in pregnancy management is recommended.</string>


</resources>
