<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BeZikaFree</string>

    <string name="symptoms_title">What are the symptoms of Zika?</string>
    <string name="symptoms_text">The Zika virus commonly causes a mild flu-like illness that might include fever, headache, joint and or muscle pain, conjunctivitis (“pink eye”) and sometimes a body rash.\n\nMost people infected with Zika virus won’t have symptoms. For this reason, many people might not realize they have been infected. It is estimated that only one out of five infected people will have symptoms. The most common symptoms of Zika are fever, rash, joint pain, or conjunctivitis (red eyes). Other common symptoms include muscle pain and headache.\n\nThe illness is usually mild. Symptoms begin 3 to 7 days after being infected and can last for several days to a week. People usually don’t get sick enough to go to the hospital, and they very rarely die of Zika.\n\nZika virus usually remains in the blood of an infected person for about a week but it can be found longer in some people. Once a person has been infected, he or she is likely to be protected from future infections.\n\nSee your doctor or other healthcare provider if you are pregnant and develop a fever, rash, joint pain, or red eyes within 2 weeks after traveling to a place where Zika has been reported. Be sure to tell your doctor or other healthcare provider where you traveled.</string>
    <string name="overview_title">What is Zika?</string>
    <string name="overview_text">The Zika virus is a mosquito-borne illness, meaning people can get the virus by being bitten by an infected mosquito. Zika virus is related to dengue, yellow fever and West Nile Virus. It was first identified in 1947. In 2013 there were outbreaks of illness from Zika virus in several Pacific islands. More recently, the virus has been reported in many Central and South American countries. Beginning in late 2015, cases of Zika virus have been reported in some U.S. states. These are people who were infected while traveling to these countries.</string>
    <string name="transmission_mosquito_title">Through Mosquito Bites</string>
    <string name="transmission_mosquito_text">Zika virus is transmitted to people primarily through the bite of an infected Aedes species mosquito (A. aegypti and A. albopictus). These are the same mosquitoes that spread dengue and chikungunya viruses. \n\n These mosquitoes typically lay eggs in and near standing water in things like buckets, bowls, animal dishes, flower pots and vases. They prefer to bite people, and live indoors and outdoors near people. \n\n Mosquitoes become infected when they feed on a person already infected with the virus. Infected mosquitoes can then spread the virus to other people through bites.</string>
    <string name="transmissin_mother_title">From Mother to Child</string>
    <string name="transmission_mother_text">A pregnant woman can pass Zika virus to her fetus during pregnancy. Zika is a cause of microcephaly and other severe fetal brain defects. We are studying the full range of other potential health problems that Zika virus infection during pregnancy may cause.\n\n A pregnant woman already infected with Zika virus can pass the virus to her fetus during the pregnancy or around the time of birth.\n\n To date, there are no reports of infants getting Zika virus through breastfeeding. Because of the benefits of breastfeeding, mothers are encouraged to breastfeed even in areas where Zika virus is found.</string>
    <string name="transmission_transfusion_title">Through Blood Transfusion</string>
    <string name="transmission_transfusion_text">As of February, 1, 2016, there have not been any confirmed blood transfusion transmission cases in the United States.\n\n There have been multiple reports of blood transfusion transmission cases in Brazil. These reports are currently being investigated.\n\n During the French Polynesian outbreak, 2.8% of blood donors tested positive for Zika and in previous outbreaks, the virus has been found in blood donors.</string>
    <string name="transmission_sex_title">Through Sexual Contact</string>
    <string name="transmission_sex_text">Zika virus can be spread by a man to his sex partners.\n\n In known cases of sexual transmission, the men developed Zika virus symptoms. From these cases, we know the virus can be spread when the man has symptoms, before symptoms start and after symptoms resolve.\n\n In one case, the virus was spread a few days before symptoms developed.\n\n The virus is present in semen longer than in blood.</string>
    <string name="transmission_father_title">What if the father of the baby is infected with the Zika virus or has been in an area where Zika is active?</string>
    <string name="transmission_father_text">Zika virus can be found in semen and sexual transmission of the virus has been reported. We do not know how often Zika infection can be found in semen or how long the virus can be present in semen. Consistent and regular condom use is recommended for women if a man has a current diagnosis of Zika infection, a man has symptoms of Zika, or a man has recently been in a place where there is known Zika transmission, even if he has had no symptoms. A man who has returned from an area of active Zika transmission but has not had any symptoms should consider using a condom for 28 days after his return to prevent the chance of sexual transmission to his non-pregnant partner.</string>


</resources>
